All right, this is Aaron and Sammy. Week
five of training. Week four got deleted
inadvertently. Uh, my computer crashed,
but now I've got a Mac, so hopefully
we're good to go. Here's Aaron doing
sumo deadlifts with
135. Uh, not a problem for her. This is
Sammy squatting 135. It's funny. Look at
the back. Look at her. A little bit of
buttwink going on. See her low back
starts to round. This clears up as the
weight gets heavier. All right, here's
Aaron. This is
155. This just flies up. This is easy
for
her. Uh, now here's Sammy with 185. Back
position is even
better.
Uh, Aaron here now with 175 lb sumo
deadlift. Her her record was a 185
before this day. Here's Sammy. This is
205. This is a PR for her. Look at that
back
position. Very good. Uh, so there's a
205 pound squat. That's a PR for her.
And this is 195. So this is a PR for
Aaron. Uh, but she goes heavier. And now
here's Aaron. Uh, sorry, Sammy with a
185 squat for four reps. So she gets
four reps here. That's also a rep PR
with 185. Look at that back position is
incredible. Um, so I was very happy with
her squats uh on this day. Sammy's very
hip dominant. Okay, here's 205. This is
the most Aaron has ever
deadlifted. Uh, she is funny. She told
me she'd get 205. I didn't I didn't I
was I didn't think she'd quite get it,
but she did. Was very impressed. Here's
Sammy warming up with deadlifts. This
185, no problem for
her. All right. Now, here's Aaron
warming up with squats with 95 pounds.
It's funny. When she first started, this
was her max. And now this is just she
could get it for like probably 10 or 12
reps, maybe even 15 if she really wanted
to. Okay, this is 225
uh for
Sammy. Uh at this point, I just have
Sammy doing conventional pulls and Aaron
doing sumo. Okay, this is
115. Aaron busts out a few reps.
Um, oh, let's see how many she gets.
This is four.
Oh, nice. Okay, she So, she gets five
with 115. Um, and now here is Sammy with
a I think that's a 275 lb deadlift.
That's a PR for her. She was very wobbly
on that one, but that was a that was 275
pounds. That was a
PR. So, uh, very happy with the girls
performance. This is Aaron doing a
65lb wide grip bench press. Aaron is
actually stronger close grip. And then
here's Sammy with 65
lbs.
Um, now we've got 85 lbs on the
bar. Uh, Aaron gets one. Here's 95
pounds with Sammy. She gets his easy
uh blows that up.
um gets a triple with 95 lbs.
So, and then here is Aaron. This is a
PR, I believe, with wide grip. She'd
never done 95 lbs before with wide grip.
Uh this is Sammy with 85
lbs. Can't remember how many reps she
gets.
Two,
three,
four, five. Oh, she keeps
going. Six reps. That was very good. Six
reps. Okay, here's Aaron. This is uh 65
lbs. So, she's wrapping out with 65
um
Just trying to get some volume in
because the girls have not been training
much. Um, oh, this is 75 lbs. So, what I
like is the girls are holding really
good
position. Okay, here's
Sammy with a leg press.
Uh, this is what, eight plates. I really
love this Cybex. It's actually called a
squat press, but Sammy's got really
strong hips. This one, this is a leg
press that's very hip dominant.
Um, it's funny. It's called a leg press.
It's also called a hip sled, but it
really works both. This Cybex works both
the legs and the hips real well. So,
let's see. 8* 45 is what? 360. This is
360 lbs. Um, and now here's
Aaron. This is Aaron's
um second time doing these. This was
heavy for her when she first started.
And then this looks very easy on this
day. So, we need to go up and wait.
U She needs to quit looking from side to
side when she does
these. So, this is six plates. What is
that?
270. And I can't I am not good at
counting reps. I think she gets like 15
or 20 or something like
that. So, next week we'll go up and
wait. I like this as an assistance lift
for Aaron because when she finishes
this, her quads are smoked.
Okay, here's Sammy doing dumbbell
military press.
25. Uh, this our first time doing seated
dumbbell military. I had him do 20s. I
should have had him do 25s or 30s. This
is too light. I think she gets 12
reps. This is really bad recording on my
part with the video because I'm also
using my phone my for Instagram. So,
it's my bad.
I'm trying to put clips on Instagram.
Um, so I think she gets 12. And then
here's Aaron. I don't like those elbows
out so much. I like her doing more uh
elbows tucked
and a narrower coming down all the
way. Um, so that's better full range. I
think she gets 13 or 14 or something. So
this is with the 20 lb dumbbells. Next
week we'll go heavier. 25s or 30s.
I should probably use that use a uh I
should lower the seat on that bench,
too, for
Aaron. She's kind of like semi-standing.
So, I just had him do one set of
dumbbell military. They were in a hurry,
didn't have a lot of extra time. Okay,
next up is uh Sammy doing barbell hip
thrust. This is 225 lbs.
I think she gets 12 or let's see, two,
three. She's just flying up on these
now. Four,
five, 6, 7,
8, 9,
10, 11,
12,
13,
14, 15. Yep. So, she gets 15 reps. I
think she's done 20 reps with this.
Might be 245. I don't know. I wasn't
paying attention.
She's almost close to her previous
all-time strongest on hip thrust. Okay,
this is Aaron with 225. And um I can't
God, I wasn't counting. I can't remember
how many she got. Maybe it was like
eight or something, but she wasn't happy
with it. So, she wanted to do a set of
bands afterwards, but Sammy was fried
from her set. So, we didn't do bands
band hip thrust with Sammy. We did band
hip thrust with Aaron. Okay, this is
Sammy with a 60 lb
uh back raise or 60 lb 45 degree hyper.
She's really strong at these. Look at
her just fling the weight up like it's
nothing. She gets 20 reps here. So,
um Sammy does really well with high rep
glute stuff, but she hates doing high
reps. It's kind of funny. Probably
because she's so good at it, it kills
her. So, she got 20 reps with the 60.
And then Aaron does Aaron wanted to do
some extra glute stuff. So, she threw on
the band and did I
believe not sure how many reps she gets
here. Maybe 15 or so.
Um, I think the the girls uh both prefer
using
bands, but Sammy likes barbell and
bands. Aaron much prefers the bands for
hip
thrust. Um,
but I'm not counting. I think she gets
20.
Maybe more. She's gotten really good at
these. This used to be hard for her when
she started out. Actually, she couldn't
do this much weight. Now she's and her
glutes have gotten a lot bigger since
she
started. Um, and now here's Aaron with
the I think this is 60. Yep, that's a 60
pounder. This is the most weight she's
used on these two. Let's see. Three.
Four. That's really hard to hold. Five.
Six. Seven. I think she gets
eight. Eight reps. So that was good.
Okay. Now this is actually another
training session now. So this is
uh this is this training session is from
today the 31st Halloween. So this
is 10:31. This is Sammy with a set of
three uh squats with 185. She does three
sets of three with 185. Here's her
second set. Her knees were caving
slightly on that first uh set. So,
let's see. I told her, watch the knee
position and the back position. I told
her I don't care if she quite hits
parallel. Um, so this is her third set.
She gets three again.
I know she can always go a little bit
deeper if she wants, but I was happy
with really happy with this today
because this is the first time she's
gotten 185 for three sets of
three. Um, and her back position looked
really good. Okay,
here's uh Sammy with deadlifts. This is
uh this is
245. She gets 245 for three.
So, that's a PR for Sammy. Uh, she does
two sets of that. Okay, here's Aaron.
This is 115
pounds. Uh, and she gets three sets of
three with 115. So, this was a very good
uh workout for Aaron, too.
Yep. So, three reps. Here's Sammy. This
is 245 again.
Sammy's a little bit wobbly on her
deadlifts, but
happy with this workout today. Looked
pretty easy for her. So, she got two
sets of three with
245. Okay, Sam. Uh, here's uh Aaron
again with 115. Form looks
great. Little bit squirmy on that rep.
And here's rep three.
Looks good. She's getting depth. And
then here's her third set of
three. Uh,
yep. Form looks great.
I think this set her form looked better
than the first two sets. There she just
grinds that one out. Okay, now we're on
bench press. This is Sammy with a 95
pound bench press.
Uh, I just told her to do two this set
and then I realized it looked really
easy, so I had her do three the next
set. Okay, this is Aaron. This is a 10
and this is 175 sumo deadlift. She got
three and it just looked so easy for
her. I told her get three reps with 175.
So, next set we went up. Here's Sammy
again with 95 pound bench press. Sammy's
bench has taken off.
Um, Explode up. Come on.
Uh, gets three reps there.
So, here's Aaron. Uh, he's up. This is
lbs. This looks pretty
easy. She's just warming up. Knees up.
Here's
115. Uh,
again, easy easy weight for her. Um,
and uh, this is the week of the
competition. So, this is five days out
before the comp. Here's
135. Actually had her do three singles
with 135.
Nice. That's her second single.
And then here is her third single.
Looking pretty easy. And then we did
145.
So, uh, based on this, we're I'm
thinking she'll get 145 to 150.
And I went down to 95 lbs and had her
pause at parallel.
Just do 3 second pauses. She likes to
rush these pauses. If I say three, I
count down 3 seconds.
She'll really get probably two seconds.
Um, there's another pause.
One, two, three.
Last one.
One, two, three. Yep. So, I had her do
two sets of pause squats. Maybe I had to
do knees out. Yep. Three sets. Oh, here
I just had her do explosive squats with
95.
Uh, I think I just told her to do five
reps really explosively. This was her
one rep max when she started. Good.
Yep. Um, all right. Sumo deads. This is
135. I didn't want her to pull too heavy
today. Uh because she's training again
in 5 days. So, I think I had her do five
reps with 135 and then just a single
with
185. Uh yeah, this is
185. Just had her do a single. She did
205 earlier in the week.
Um, guess I had her do two
singles.
Yep. Now, here's bench
press. This is 75 lbs.
Uh, she gets it
for three reps. No, this is 85 lbs.
Gets it for a single. And this is 95
lbs. Gets it halfway up. Couldn't get
it. Now, here's one, two, three. 65
pounds. I made her pause at the chest.
One, two, three. Had her do this for two
sets. I think she gets about six reps on
both of them. One, two, three.
But, uh, one, two. It's good for her to
get used to this. A longer pause.
At the competition, it's going to be
tough. Good. And make sure she pauses
long enough. And then here's her last
set of paws, bend press.
So Sammy doesn't she recovers quickly.
Most experienced powerlifters taper a
lot before meet.
But these girls have just been training
for six weeks. They don't need to taper
so much. Uh they've been going up
consistently each week. One, two, three.
And I think they'll do the same thing at
the competition. I think they'll match.
I'm hoping they'll match their previous
bets or maybe even go a little get like
five or five or 10 pounds heavier on
certain lifts. Here's leg press. This is
eight plates. So, what 360? So, this is
the most Aaron's
done. Um I think she gets two sets of
five on these.
Um yep, there's her second set. She
really feels these a ton in her quads.
So, I think these help her deadlift.
Uh, help her use more leg drive in a
deadlift.
Nice. Lock it. Good.
Um, and then I had her do band back
extensions. These are tough. I'm not
sure exactly how much weight is at the
top. probably like it's probably like 15
lb 20 lb at the bottom and about 65 lb
at the top. Go. So, she she did two sets
of 10ish. Three. Four. Come up higher.
Five. Good. 10 or 12. I can't remember
exactly how many she got. Eight. Nine.
Hold this. 10. Come up higher. Hold
it. Good. Go for it.
And then we just had her finish off with
some band tricep extensions to try to
build some triceps lockout strength
before the
comp. Aaron usually trains several days
a week. So she's it's going to be hard
for her to take off Wednesday, Thursday,
Friday, three days in a row with the
meat on
Saturday. Okay, here's Sammy. this 135
pound squat.
She was looking strong today. I could
tell this looks like nothing. It's just
flying up. Um, good for now. This is
185. And look great, Sammy.
Now, this is 210. So, this is a one rep
max for Sammy. This is the heaviest
she's ever gone. Nice. Come on. And she
sinks it to parallel and locks it out.
So, this is a new one rep max. Go for
it. Now I had to do pause squats with
135.
It was kind of funny is Yeah, I had
Sammy do
a new max though. Good. Last one five
days before the meet. Two, but uh she
doesn't get beat up much. I wouldn't do
that with an experienced lifter, but
Sammmy is she's been training for
powerlifting for six weeks, so you can
do these sort of things with beginners.
Two, three. Uh two sets of pause squats.
One, two, three. 3 second pause. Three.
Go. Uh, now here's deadlifts. This is
225. And it was just the weight was
flying up. She gets six reps here. It
just looks like nothing. So,
um, I decided to be, uh, you know, this
is a record. Six reps is a record and it
just looked easy. So, I decided to go
heavier. And uh we went for a one rep
max deadlift as well. Ready when you
are. So this is actually 285. She's
never done this much before. And boom.
Locks out 285.
Now here's the leg press. This is 10
plates. So 450 lb leg presses. Good.
And think she gets three.
Good. Three reps. Get tight. Here's
bench press. 95 lbs. Good. She gets a
single. I had her try 115, which she has
done this before, I think,
and not today. She got it about halfway
up. Couldn't get it. Now I have her do
95 lbs for a
triple. Very good form on this set. Give
me one more.
I haven't been focusing much on bench
press.
Um, another set of leg press. 450.
She gets three again.
Squeaks out four maybe.
Yep. Four reps there. And now finally,
this is hip thrust.
This is
uh this is
3:15
5 six reps with
315. And then uh we put on
uh okay this tricep extensions with the
band a little if that helps.
Totally lean forward a little. We
haven't been working triceps. I just
haven't been focusing on the bench press
that much with the ladies. There things
I could do to make their bench stronger,
but not a huge priority for
um now this is the one rep m sorry a
three rep max for Sammy. This is a 365
lb hip thrust. So that's rep
two. And that's rep three.
Okay. So here's clips that I had on my
phone
uh from over the past few weeks. That's
Aaron getting a 155 squat. That was
actually her one rep max.
There's Sammy with a 265 lb deadlift.
This was her previous one rep max.
Uh
Sammy squatting 95 for reps. She got six
reps.
This
was uh a couple weeks ago.
Got any more in you? Keep going. Keep
going if you can.
You got Aaron with a 185 lb deadlift
conventional. This was the most she got
conventional. Oh, didn't get it. That
was too much.
Sammy with a 205 pound squat deep. This
was her previous one rep max. That was a
little choppy. Nice.
Um I think I had her do it again.
Descend. Keep that arch. More recently
she got 210. So this is 5 lbs under her
one rep max.
Aaron with band. Good band hip
thrust. High reps. Actually, I think
this is a blue and green
band. She gets like
15 or 20 or something like that. Two
more. Come up higher.
Last one. Hold it. 10 seconds. This is
uh helped Aaron steadily increase her
glute size, which
has to help out for sure. Here's
Sammy. Sammy makes this look easy. Got
incredible endrange glute strength.
Move higher. Five
more. Now hold this last one. One. Was
that 20? 10 seconds. Keep going. Long
pause there. That's harder than it
looks.
Good. Now, here's Aaron with a 50 lb
back extension. Squeeze glutes.
Let me get this right. You've never seen
the Wizard of
Glutes. Nice. There you go. Yeah, pretty
one in film history.
This is Sammy with a 95 lb bench
press.
Um, let's see. What is this? A 225 lb
deadlift.
She gets five reps.
So that was her previous best.
This is Aaron squatting. This is 115.
participate in the contemporary.
That's right. She squatted 115 for five
here, which one more.
She should
get six. 115 for six. That was her
best. This is a 255 lb dead for Sammy.
And she gets two reps.
actually. Wow. She gets three reps.
Three ups is
255. Uh
Sammy got another in you. That's 135 lb
deadlift. She gets three. Blow it up.
Come on.
There's Sammy trying 275.
Not getting it.
This is a 155 lb
squat, Sammy.
Nice. One more.
Now, here's Aaron doing a one. Come on,
Eric. Nice.
Sammy with a 185 lb squat. Great.
Great back position.
Gets three reps.
Two, three, go. Come on. Sammy or Aaron.
That was a 205 lb deadlift. She did not
get it. She ended up getting that a
couple weeks
later. Uh here's Sammy with a 20. She
did not get this. was your only squat
fail during the 6 weeks. 205 lb squat.
Nice. Aaron with a What is that? Oh,
that that was a 205 lb deadlift. She got
it.
We use the other bench next set. This is
Sammy with a
85 lb bench
press. Close grip.
This is close grip. Two more. Come on.
And I believe she gets six reps.
Five
reps. Now this is 95
lbs. She gets one rep. Close
grip. Here's Aaron. Tries 95 lbs.
Couldn't get it. The explosive. Come on.
This is Sammy. Two. 225 lbs.
7 I think that's 225. Can't see the end
of the plates.
Uh Aaron, I guess this looks like 135.
I'm up high. Good.
Can't tell. Maybe it's Hold it. Less
more. It's probably heavier than that.
Seven 8 9 10. Good.
Um Sammy doing band hip thrust.
Dust proof Samsung Galaxy S4. It's
oopsroof.
And baby. More.
vacation.
Sammy does not like to rep out, so she
gets amazing. You might say the Samsung
Galaxy S4 Active is waterproof.
Oh, man. Tries to fake like she's
reach failure when she's not even close
cuz she hates high reps. So, this is a
drop set. So, I had her do
a blue and a green band and then take
the green band off and do as many with
the blue band.
feast one
drop at the top.
Now I had Aaron do the same thing I
believe.
Drop
set. I can't.
Seriously? So, you just got into an
accident. Thankfully, nobody's hurt, but
your car is in bad shape. Your insurance
company referred
to the blue and the green would like to
offer you a better
option. We took off the blue. So, the
green
legend, the original home of the wave,
your deductible. It takes just one
person to change one life.
Make sure
uh this is Aaron with a 135 lb squat.
This is Aaron with 145 lb squat.
This is Aaron with a 185 lb deadlift.
This is Aaron with
a 360 leg
press. Come on. One more. Explode up.
Stand your heels. Good.
Squeeze glutes. Come up higher. Two with
band back extensions. Four. Come up
higher. Five. Good. Six. 10. Seven.
Eight. Nine. Hold this 10th one. Come up
higher. Hold it.
Good. Here's
Sammy. This is a 210 lb squat. This is a
one rep max for her.
Nice. Come on. Reaches parallel. Keep
the spine in good position. This is
Sammy with 225 lb dead for six.
Good. Just plate is just flying up.
Now, this is uh Sammy with a
285B one rep max.
Now, this is a 365 lb hip thrust. She
gets three reps. Nice.
And this is a three rep max for
Sammy. Crazy. 365 lbs.
It's not